Rohit Sahu

Web Developer

Web Developer with 2+ years of experience in designing and developing user interfaces, testing, debugging. I've extensive experience using multiple standard programming languages. Proven ability in optimizing web functionalities that improve data retrieval and workflow efficiencies.



- Guwahati, India
- in linkedin.com/in/rtsu
- f facebook.com/rernr
- 🖹 stackoverflow.com/users/12099177/rohit-sahu

- _ +918402081401
- rohit52594.github.io
- S rohit52594@outlook.com
- github.com/rohit52594
- medium.com/@rohitsahu728

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jr. Software Developer Soffront Corporation.

09/2021 - Present

Kolkata

Working in React.js to build and solve issues in the CRM

Web DeveloperOdometry Technix

04/2019 - 08/2021

Guwahati

Working as a Web Developer with React, Node.js, PHP. Growing here with learning and using tools like AWS, Firebase, Codeigniter, Laravel, React using Hooks, Node.js, etc.

Intern

DiTech Process Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

11/2018 - 03/2019

Guwahati

Done Internship here as On Job Trainee. Learned working with XHTML, CSS3 for making EPUB's and working with XML files, document management, etc.

EDUCATION

Master's in Computer Applications

Manipal University, Jaipur

10/2021 - Present

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

Nazira College

06/2015 - 12/2018

Nazira, Sivasagar

Microsoft Certified Systems Expert ATL Infosys

09/2018 - 02/2019

Guwahati

Courses

 The primary topics in MCSE (Microsoft Certified Systems Expert) are: Windows Server. Active Directory Installation, DHCP, IP Addressing, LAN Configuration, Group Policy Object & OU.

SKILLS

React.js AWS PHP Node.js Linux

AOP/OOP MaterialUI jQuery Git SSH

PROJECTS

Onor

Used React.js and redux

takenstar.com

Used react redux with express in backend.

Monthly Gold Investment Plan

EMI Management system

buysara.com

E-commerce application developed in Codeigniter

Tambola

Tambola game front end in react and backend in codeigniter

patidarrangcollege.com

Admission portal developed in Codeigniter

Others...

 Some other projects such as Inventory Management, MLM, CMS, booking portals etc.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Web Developer (07/2015 - 06/2016) - NAASCOM

Junior Web Developer from NSQF Level 5

LANGUAGES

Hindi

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

Assamese

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Listening to Music

Cooking

Coding

Travelling

Video Games